在之前的讲座中，我们谈了很多关于物体的位置和方向
In previous lectures, we talked a lot about the position and orientation of objects in
世界。在这个讲座中，我们将讨论位置的变化率
the world. In this lecture, we're going to talk about the rate of change of position
和取向的变化率。我们要谈论速度。
and the rate of change of orientation. We're going talk about velocities.
在这张照片中，我们可以看到一个球在空中移动。在我们说什么之前
In this picture, we can see a ball moving through the air. Before we can say anything
关于球的速度或位置有意义，我们需要引入一个参考
meaningful about the velocity or position of the ball, we need to introduce a reference
坐标框架。到目前为止，这是我们熟悉的概念。
coordinate frame. By now this is a familiar concept to us.
现在我可以谈论球的速度，我用这个蓝色矢量来描述
Now I can talk about the velocity of the ball and I describe that by this blue vector which
我标记为V.所以V是速度矢量，它描述了方向和幅度
I've labeled V. So V is the velocity vector and that describes the direction and the magnitude
在这个特定时刻的球的运动或球的位置变化率。
of the motion or the rate of change of position of the ball at this particular moment in time.
这张照片拍摄的那一刻。
The moment when this photograph was taken.
现在速度是矢量。它有3个组件相对于坐标定义
Now velocity is a vector quantity. It's got 3 components defined with respect to the coordinate
框架，这是X坐标的变化率，即x点。变化率
frame and that is the rate of change of the X coordinate, that's x dot. The rate of change
Y坐标和Z坐标的变化率。
of the Y coordinate and the rate of change of the Z coordinate.
现在我们可以考虑飞盘在空中飞行的更复杂的运动
Now we can consider the rather more complex motion of a Frisbee flying through the air
再一次，我们可以说出有关位置或速度的任何有意义的事情
and once again before we can say anything meaningful about the position or velocity
对象，我们需要定义一个参考坐标系。现在飞盘已经到了
of this object, we need to define a reference coordinate frame. Now the Frisbee has got
速度的平移。它正在从投掷它的人的空气中移动
a translational of velocity. It's moving through the air from the person who threw it to the
它要降落的地方，但飞盘也旋转，我们说飞盘已经到了
place where its going to land but the Frisbee also spins and we say the Frisbee has got
一个角速度，这里用红色矢量表示我称之为欧米茄。
an angular velocity and that's denoted here by the red vector that I've called omega.
平移速度V和角速度ω再次连续变化
Once again the translational velocity V and the angular velocity omega change continually
当物体在移动。所以这些矢量代表平移和角速度
as the object is moving. So these vectors represent translational and angular velocity
在这张照片拍摄的那一刻。角速度，即红色矢量
at the instant that this picture was taken. The angular velocity, that's the red vector
在这里，有一个方向，这是身体在此旋转的轴
here, has got a direction and that is the axis about which the body is rotating at this
特别是时间瞬间，这个向量的大小是周围的旋转速度
particular instant in time and the magnitude of this vector is the rate of rotation around
那个轴。如果物体旋转得非常快，那么角速度矢量
that axis. If the object was spinning very quickly, then the angular velocity vector
会很长。再次，角速度矢量有3个分量，所以我们
would be very long. Once again, the angular velocity vector has got 3 components so we
可以采用这个红色矢量，我们可以描述关于X，Y和Z的组件
can take this red vector and we can describe components with respect to the X, Y, and Z
参考坐标系的轴。
axis of a reference coordinate frame.
现在不仅仅是飞盘和球具有平移和旋转速度。
Now it's not just Frisbee and balls that have got translational and rotational velocity.
机器人手臂的末端执行器通常具有平移速度和角速度
The end effector of a robot arm has a translational velocity and an angular velocity and often
我们需要指定这些是什么，实际上命令机器人关节，以便我们得到
we need to specify what these are and in fact command the robot joints so that we get the
期望的机器人末端执行器的平移和角速度。
desired translational and angular velocity of the robot’s end effector.
通常我们堆叠平移速度的元素，元素VX，VY和VZ以及
Typically we stack the elements of the translational velocity, the elements VX, VY and VZ and the
角速度的元素，欧米茄x，欧米茄y和欧米茄z成为一个向量。
elements of the angular velocity, omega x, omega y and omega z into one vector.
这是六个元素长，我们称之为空间速度或扭曲
That's six elements long and we refer to this as the spatial velocity or the twist of the
宾语。我们使用希腊字母nu看起来有点像V来表示这个特殊的数量，
object. We use the greek letter nu which looks a bit like a V to denote this special quantity,
这个空间速度或扭曲有6个元素。这是一个六元素矢量。
this spatial velocity or twist which has got 6 elements. It's a six element vector.